JESULOBA JOHN ABERE

jesulobajohn@gmail.com \diamond Github \diamond LinkedIn \diamond Portfolio

SUMMARY

Forward-thinking Software Engineer with a strong focus on optimizing user experience. Skilled in developing functional and responsive web, back-end, and mobile applications. A collaborative team player dedicated to achieving project objectives with efficiency and precision.

SKILLS

Languages

Javascript, Typescript, Python, Go, C++, Java

Technologies

React, Next.js, React-Native, Redux, Zustand, Mobx, Graphql, Git, Django, Node.js, Express, Cypress, Heroku, Solidity, Tailwind, AWS, styled-components, Docker, React-query, Jest

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Engineer

Aug 2022 - present

Sidebrief

- Developed modern web applications that served both internal and external users, resulting in a 20% increase in user engagement and a 15% improvement in customer satisfaction ratings.
- Collaborated with product managers and designers to create wireframes, mockups, and prototypes for new web applications, resulting in a 40% decrease in development time.
- Implemented seamless integration of 3rd party APIs, reducing development time by 30% and improving overall system performance by 25%.
- Scrutinized and made clear and informed decisions about technology and architecture choices, resulting in a 25% improvement in system efficiency and a 15% reduction in maintenance costs.

Full-stack Developer

Sept 2020 - Aug 2022

Maze-softwares

- Accomplished significant milestones by successfully designing major new features in an iterative, high-quality, and scalable way, resulting in a 30% increase in user engagement and a 20% improvement in customer satisfaction ratings.
- Closely monitored the performance of the web stack, responding to system failures within minutes and achieving a 99.9% uptime, ensuring uninterrupted service for users.
- Developed and implemented a suite of APIs using Python/Django, resulting in a 30% reduction in overall system latency and increasing API uptime by 10%.
- Collaborated with UX designers and product managers to ensure creative proposals aligned with design best practices and stakeholder expectations.

Software Engineering Intern

Feb 2020 - Sept 2020

Needle inc.

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to integrate third-party APIs into existing systems, resulting in a 50% reduction in manual data entry errors.
- Revamped CSS structure, reducing load time by 40% and improving user experience for the visitors.
- Implemented responsive design principles into all web applications, optimizing mobile user experiences and increasing mobile traffic by 50%.

EDUCATION